<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache Ozone</title>
    <link>https://ozone.apache.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Apache Ozone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year} The Apache Software Foundation</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ozone.apache.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.1.0 available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/2.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/2.1.0/</guid>
      <description>Release Note Apache Ozone 2.1.0 adds 805 new features, improvements and bug fixes on top of Ozone 2.0.
Notable Changes   HDDS-10239 | Storage Container Reconciliation  Introduced a container reconciliation protocol to resolve mismatched container states and verify replica integrity.
  HDDS-12940 | Ozone Snapshot Phase 3: Scale up Snapshot Operations  Enhanced Ozone Snapshot scalability and continued stability improvements.
  HDDS-8387 | Container and volume scanners phase II  Enhanced storage volume failure handling by introducing a &amp;lsquo;degraded&amp;rsquo; state to preserve data availability, along with improved health observability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.0.0 available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/2.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/2.0.0/</guid>
      <description>Release Notes Apache Ozone 2.0.0 adds 1708 new features, improvements and bug fixes on top of Ozone 1.4.
  HDDS-10295 | Major | Provide an &amp;ldquo;ozone repair&amp;rdquo; subcommand to update the snapshot info in transactionInfoTable  A new command &amp;ldquo;ozone repair update-transaction&amp;rdquo; is added to update the highest index in OM transactionInfoTable.
  HDDS-11258 | Blocker | [hsync] Add new OM layout version  A new layout version, HBASE_SUPPORT (7) is added to Ozone Manager that provides the guardrail for the full support of hsync, lease recovery and listOpenFiles APIs for HBase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.4.1 available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.4.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.4.1/</guid>
      <description>Apache Ozone 1.4.1 is a minor bug fix release that addresses several issues to enhance stability and reliability compared to version 1.4.0. For a detailed list of commits and resolved JIRA issues in this release, please refer to Changes between ozone-1.4.0 and ozone-1.4.1 on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.4.0 available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.4.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.4.0/</guid>
      <description>Apache Ozone 1.4.0 is released with following features:
 Snapshots Erasure Coding V2: offline reconstruction, container balancer support Recon: heat maps, more diagnose info Certificate auto-rotation SCM decommissioning Improved OM decommissioning Symmetric key-based block/container token implementation Quota on FSO bucket  This is a generally available (GA) release. It represents a point of API stability and quality that we consider production-ready.
Image credit: Hot Springs Mountain Tower by Jeremy Thompson, CC BY 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.3.0 available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.3.0/</guid>
      <description>Apache Ozone 1.3.0 is released with following features:
 Erasure Coding - V1 support (Online reconstruction support) Container balancer Limit number of rocksdb instances to 1 per disk on high-density datanodes Ozone S3 Multi-tenancy Support S3 Grpc improvements for metadata path Filesystem Optimized and Object Store bucket layout types  This is a generally available (GA) release. It represents a point of API stability and quality that we consider production-ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.2.1 available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.2.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.2.1/</guid>
      <description>Apache Ozone 1.2.1 is released with following features:
 Non-rolling downgrade support to 1.1.0 Storage Container Manager high availability for new clusters Filesystem prefix optimization for new clusters Transparent data encryption for S3 buckets Security enhancements  This is a generally available (GA) release. It represents a point of API stability and quality that we consider production-ready.
Image credit: Glacier National Park 8 by Tony Hisgett, CC BY 2.0 / Text added to original</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.1.0 available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.1.0/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 1.1.0 is released with following features:
 Volume/Bucket Quota Support Security related enhancements ofs/o3fs performance improvements with Teragen and Spark Recon improvements  This is a generally available (GA) release. It represents a point of API stability and quality that we consider production-ready.
Image credit: diana_robinson , CC BY-NC-ND 2.0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.0.0 available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/1.0.0/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 1.0.0 is released with following features:
 OM HA - HA support for Ozone Manager Security Phase II Support Hadoop 2.7 &amp;amp; security enabled Hadoop 2.x Ozone OFS new Filesystem scheme Ozone Filesystem performance improvement Recon &amp;amp; Recon UI improvements Bucket link &amp;amp; S3 volume/bucket mapping changes  This is a generally available (GA) release. It represents a point of API stability and quality that we consider production-ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.5.0-beta available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.5.0-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.5.0-beta/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 0.5.0-beta is released with following features:
 O3FS - S3A based file system semantics Able to handle 1 billion objects Network topology awareness for block placement GDPR Right to Erasure  This is a beta release and not production ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.4.1-alpha available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.4.1-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.4.1-alpha/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 0.4.1-alpha is released with following features:
 Ozone Native ACL support First class K8s support Stability improvements  This is an alpha release and not production ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.4.0-alpha available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.4.0-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.4.0-alpha/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 0.4.0-alpha is released with following features:
 Hadoop Delegation Tokens and Block Tokens supported for Ozone. Transparent Data Encryption (TDE) Support - Allows data blocks to be encrypted-at-rest. Kerberos support for Ozone. Certificate Infrastructure for Ozone - Tokens use PKI instead of shared secrets. Datanode to Datanode communication secured via mutual TLS. Ability secure ozone cluster that works with Yarn, Hive, and Spark. Helm/Skaffold support to deploy Ozone clusters on K8s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.3.0-alpha available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.3.0-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.3.0-alpha/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 0.3.0-alpha is released.
 A new S3 compatible rest server is added. Ozone can be used from any S3 compatible tools (docs, HDDS-434) Ozone Hadoop file system URL prefix is renamed from o3:// to o3fs:// (HDDS-651) Extensive testing and stability improvements of OzoneFs. Spark, YARN and Hive support and stability improvements. Improved Pipeline handling and recovery. Separated/dedicated classpath definitions for all the Ozone components. (HDDS-447)  This is an alpha release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.2.1-alpha available</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.2.1-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/release/0.2.1-alpha/</guid>
      <description>This is the first version of Apache Hadoop Ozone. Ozone is an Object store for Hadoop built using Hadoop Distributed Data Store.
This release is fully functional, but alpha quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Ozone Releases</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/downloads/</guid>
      <description>Archives Releases starting with 1.1.0, when Apache Ozone became a top-level project, are available in the Ozone archives.
Releases before that can be found in Apache Hadoop archives.
Download  Download the release ozone-${OZONE_VERSION}-src.tar.gz from a mirror site. Download signature or checksum from Apache.  Verify GnuPG signature Download Ozone developers&#39; public KEYS.
gpg --import KEYS gpg --verify ozone-${OZONE_VERSION}-src.tar.gz.asc ozone-${OZONE_VERSION}-src.tar.gz SHA-512 checksum sha512sum -c ozone-${OZONE_VERSION}-src.tar.gz License The software licensed under Apache License 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/docs/</guid>
      <description>Documentation is also part of the binary release packages and available online from the running Storage Container Manager or Ozone Manager webui.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/faq/</guid>
      <description>What is Ozone? Ozone is an object store designed for big data applications. Big data workloads tend to be very different from standard workloads and Ozone is born out of lessons learned from running Hadoop in thousands of clusters.
Why an Object Store? Object stores are more straightforward to build and use than standard file systems. It is also easier to scale an object store. The fact that most big data applications and frameworks like Apache Spark, YARN and Hive can run both on cloud and on-prem, makes having an object store on-prem very attractive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozone Blogs</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/blogs/</guid>
      <description> Apache Ozone Best Practices at Didi. Hongbing Wang, Shilun Fan, and Wei Ming. Blog  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozone Community</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/community/</guid>
      <description>Ozone Mailing Lists Developers If you’d like to contribute to Ozone, please subscribe to the Ozone developer mailing list.
The Ozone developer mailing list is: dev@ozone.apache.org.
 Subscribe to List Unsubscribe from List Archives  Commits If you’d like to see changes made in the Ozone version control system, please subscribe to the Ozone commits mailing list.
The Ozone commits mailing list is: commits@ozone.apache.org.
 Subscribe to List Unsubscribe from List Archives  Issues If you’d like to see changes made in the Ozone issue tracking system, please subscribe to the Ozone issues mailing list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozone Events</title>
      <link>https://ozone.apache.org/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ozone.apache.org/events/</guid>
      <description>Past Meetups The first ever Apache Ozone User Group Summit was held at Cloudera&amp;rsquo;s headquarter on Nov 10, 2022. This event was live streamed on LinkedIn and on YouTube. Meetup link YouTube recording Slide deck
The following was the list of agenda:
 Opening, Karthik Krishnamoorthy Recording Apache Ozone - Scalable, redundant distributed object store Recording Bucket types and FSO improvements, Ethan Rose Recording Apache Ozone snapshots - new design, Prashant Pogde, Siyao Meng Recording Apache Ozone Performance, Ritesh Shukla, Recording    Past Conference Talks 2025  Apache CoC North America 2025: Apache Ozone 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
