<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Application Integrations on Ozone</title>
    <link>/integration.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Application Integrations on Ozone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/integration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hadoop DistCp</title>
      <link>/integration/distcp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/integration/distcp.html</guid>
      <description>Hadoop DistCp is a command line, MapReduce-based tool for bulk data copying.
The hadoop distcp command can be used to copy data to and from Ozone and any Hadoop compatible file systems, such as HDFS or S3A.
Basic usage To copy files from a source Ozone cluster directory to a destination Ozone cluster directory, use the following command:
hadoop distcp ofs://ozone1/vol1/bucket/dir1 ofs://ozone2/vol2/bucket2/dir2 You must define the service IDs for both ozone1 and ozone2 clusters in the ozone-site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hive</title>
      <link>/integration/hive.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/integration/hive.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Hive has supported Apache Ozone since Hive 4.0. To enable Hive to work with Ozone paths, ensure that the ozone-filesystem-hadoop3 JAR is added to the Hive classpath.
Supported Access Protocols Hive supports the following protocols for accessing Ozone data:
 ofs o3fs s3a  Supported Replication Types Hive is compatible with Ozone buckets configured with either:
 RATIS (Replication) Erasure Coding  Accessing Ozone Data in Hive Hive provides two methods to interact with data in Ozone:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impala</title>
      <link>/integration/impala.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/integration/impala.html</guid>
      <description>Starting with version 4.2.0, Apache Impala provides full support for querying data stored in Apache Ozone. To utilize this functionality, ensure that your Ozone version is 1.4.0 or later.
Supported Access Protocols Impala supports the following protocols for accessing Ozone data:
 ofs s3a  Note: The o3fs protocol is NOT supported by Impala.
Supported Replication Types Impala is compatible with Ozone buckets configured with either:
 RATIS (Replication) Erasure Coding  Querying Ozone Data with Impala Impala provides two approaches to interact with Ozone:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
